Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Vishnu Vardhan Reddy.V (1) Featured

Consultant seeking roles in Software Development, Unix Shell Scripting, Git Hub, PLSQL, SQL, Requirement Gathering, Root Cause Analysis, Performance Tuning, Unit Testing, Project Execution, Defect Tracking, Application Development, Data Warehousing, Defect Fixing



Current Designation: Consultant

Current Company: E & Y

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: INDIA, Other International Location

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: PLSQL, Unix Shell Scripting, Data Warehousing, Oracle SQL, SQL Tuning, Performance Tuning, Database

Migration, SQL, Unix

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

A passionate IT Software professional with nearly 6 years of experience in the database development process from concept through delivery of next generation applications and customizable solutions

Determined operational feasibility by defining the problem, analyzing requirements, and assessing proposed solutions Expertise in Oracle PL/SQL Packages, Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Exception Handling and Collections

Experience in handling various types performance tests; capable of writing and implemented test cases, developed testing plans and identified use cases, executed tests and analyzed

Strong knowledge in Unix Commands, SQL Queries, Oracle XML Database, Data Warehousing

Executed and contributed to full-stack application development projects, with an emphasis on front end features, browser manipulation, and cross-browser compatibility

Knowledgeable in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) methodologies like Agile

Work Experience

E & Y as Consultant Oct 2019 to Till Date

Working as Oracle DB Developer

Broadridge Technologies as Member Technical Jan 2018 to Sep 2019

HCL Technologies as Software Engineer

Feb 2015 to Jan 2018

Developing and delivering the requirements provided by the customer

Providing on-time bug free service delivery & executing inter activities initiatives R & D and POC implementation for problem resolution

Following the project life cycle methodology defined under the process framework

Recording software defects and providing technical descriptions and evidence, reviewing technical & functional design specifications for ensuring understanding of individual deliverables

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Sun Solaris, RHEL, DHS-O			
Windows XP/7, Windows 10			
UNIX Shell Scripting, PL/SQL			
SQL, XML DB, Oracle 12c			
.NET, RUBY, CAMEL			
SFTP, SCP, MailX, Mutt, Sqlplus			
Sed, SQLLDR, Intel J, Git Hub			
Git Extensions, TFS			
SQL Developer, Putty, Control-M			
Toad, Visual Studio, Eclipse			
Oracle 11g,12c			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Telugu				

Projects

Project Title: GII

Client: Dell Technologies

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Gii is a suite of applications used by sales representatives to manage offline sales. Gii is an offline ecommerce application which is internal to dell and the functionality of the application is to create customer, order and quote. Customer and order will be interfaced to OMEGA, Affinity and CHUB which are the interfaces of the Gii through AQs and Quote will be interfaced to CHUB for validations though AQs and once the validations are completed, the status of the order validation will come back to Gii as an acknowledgement

Project Title: Astrid-BAML Client: Bank of America

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Sep 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Astrid is the strategic application for the asset servicing, operational process and services which includes collecting dividends and interest payments processing of corporate actions and apply tax relief from foreign government on behalf of customers. Astrid received the data from BAML and respective custodians in SWIFT (MT 564,568,566) format, completed required changes in application and after converting messages to required format will send to the clients and shareholders

Project Title: DB Laser Nucleus Transformation

https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=dea2dc7f3a0c823cb7f60ac3e19006e00e5b0f024d105c420345460c5c0...1/22/2021

Client: Deutsche Bank

Duration: Jun 2015 - Jan 2018 Nature of Employment: Full Time Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: DB Laser Nucleus Transformation is a program to enhance the applications from Sun Solaris to dCloud environment and worked on development of shell scripts for report generation and migration of scripts from Sun Solaris Unix to Red Hat Enterprise Linux in dCloud environment and migrated database from existing platform Sun Solaris Unix to DHS-O V2 (dCloud platform) and enhanced the application functionality and resilience

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time